ROBERT C. GARCIA, Staff Sergeant, USAF

2090 Thunderchief Ct, APT C Hampton VA, 23665 (757) 690-5109 - grobert179@yahoo.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Eight years of active duty geospatial and imagery experience focused on FMV/NTM analysis, first phase reporting, and geospatial data analysis. Consistently identified as a subject matter expert (SME) among peers and lead trainer for geospatial and imagery intelligence analysts while continually seeking out educational opportunities to expand and refine my own geospatial and imagery intelligence and general knowledge bases, as well as holding a current and active TS/SCI clearance. GPC-F qualified.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan 2021 – Present 30th Intelligence Squadron, DGS-1 Langley AFB, VA

Imagery Analyst Supervisor-GEOINT lead

- Led a team of 6 Airmen to stand up an emergency team in under 24 hours and provide near-real time intelligence in support of NEO operations in Afghanistan which resulted in DGS-1 analysts creating 15 products and alerting ground forces to 9 potential threats and the safe evacuation of 122,300 personnel.
- Managed a team of 13 individuals across multiple Air Force Specialties and oversaw the production and analysis of daily and weekly activity products, deep-dive intelligence products, and disposition of forces products.
- Identified gaps in analytic tradecraft and began processes for increasing imagery skillset by implementing bi-monthly NES intelligence reports and focusing on training for preparation of NGA GEOINT Professional Certifications.

Apr 2018 – Jan 2021 JIOCEUR Analytic Center RAF Molesworth, UK Russia Maritime Analyst, Intelligence Division GEOINT (IDG)

- Conducted a one-year imagery intelligence data analysis project on five targets in 3 areas of responsibility to fulfill an intelligence gap and commander priority intelligence requirement, utilizing Cedalion and NES research leading to over 1000 SOM data points being created.
- Led the implementation of advanced, modernized analytics by trialing new technology capabilities never-before used by the NGA, improving quality and quantity of Initial Phase Intelligence Reports, saving 730 hours annually within the branch, and ensuring the error rate stayed below 1% ultimately leading the NGA to introduce the new analytics across multiple NST's.
- Exploited 8,000 images from national technical means and airborne assets, authoring 1,400 Initial Phase Intelligence Reports to provide indications and warning as a watch analyst.
- Revised 168 reportable naval order of battle within the primary analytic reference tool and established new baseline SOP requirements to meet new analytical modernization.

Nov 2016 – Apr 2018 56th Special Operations Intelligence Squadron (SOIS) Cannon AFB, NM

Geospatial Analyst, Wing Imagery

- Developed a 16-item standard operating procedure for using Socet GXP and ArcGIS, becoming standard training material for two AFSOC Wing imagery shops and decreasing the production timeline for all products by 75%.
- Aided and qualified four new analysts in three different exercises, dedicating 1000 hours and creating 500 products as the lead on-the-job trainer, increasing the shop readiness by 100%.

WORK **EXPERIENCE** (Cont.)

- Hand selected to be the joint exercise imagery lead, overseeing terrain analysis for 300 helicopter landing zones and safe infiltration and exfiltration of 500 Army Rangers and 50 Navy SEALs.
- Prepared for contingency operations and deployments by creating AOR maps depicting key lines of communication, airfields, and ports; force protection graphics of two US air bases briefed to a Security Forces Squadron; and possible employment zones of adversary weapon systems in relation to two US air bases.

Aug 2017 – Jan 2018 20th Expeditionary Special Operations Squadron (ESOS), Erbil AB, IZ **Imagery Analyst, CV-22 Analyst**

- Analyzed 18,000 kilometers of austere terrain for 20 CV-22 crew members for three task force operations over a 120-day deployment, identifying safe exfiltration routes for 51 special operations forces which resulted in 7 enemies killed in action and 151 sensitive items collected against ISIS.
- Assisted in joint mission planning by identifying helicopter landing zones across 11 designated areas, enabling 950 flight hours and the movement of 730,000lbs of equipment and 4000 personnel.
- Vetted and created landing zones for seven senior CENTCOM leaders for ley leader engagements with Iraqi senior officials to further improve relations.

Mar 2014 – Nov 2016 56th Special Operations Intelligence Squadron (SOIS) Cannon AFB,

Mission Intelligence Coordinator, Remote Piloted Aircraft Operations Center (ROC)

- Delivered 472 pre-mission briefs to 236 RPA aircrew over the course of 1000 hours, providing current air threats and target information through SIPR, SOCRATES, and SOIS systems.
- Maintained communication flow between the RPA aircrew and the Joint Terminal Attack Controller during strike events against Tier 1 targets eliminating 177 enemy combatants during vehicle follows and while targeting terrorist training camps.
- Provided critical ISR over watch of an embassy evacuation in CENTCOM, assisting aircrew and FMV analysts with defensive scans around the area and safeguarding 136 American and British civilians until safely exfiltrated.

CERTIFICATIONS Jan 2019 – GEOINT Professional Certification-Fundamentals (GPC-F); Jan '19-Jan '21

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT & Oct2018 – Airman Leadership School **TRAINING**

Feb 2020 - Geospatial-Intelligence Craftsman Upgrade Training-7 Level

Aug 2018 – Principles of Instruction Course

Dec 2014 - Geospatial-Intelligence Journeyman Upgrade Training-5 Level

Mar 2014 – Geospatial-Intelligence Analyst Course

Nov 2013 - Geospatial-Intelligence Analysis Fundamentals Course

SECURITY CLEARANCE Current TS/SCI (DCID 1/14 Eligible) periodic reinvestigation of SBI/SSBI /07 Mar 2020;

EDUCATION

Jun 2023 (Expected) Arizona State University, Online Tempe, AZ

Bachelor of Science in Geographic Information Systems

Nov 2019 Community College of the Air Force Montgomery, AL

Associate in Applied Science, Intelligence Studies & Technology

AWARDS

NGA Meritorious Unit Citation – Aug 2019 Air Force Achievement Medal - Apr 2018 Meritorious Unit Award – Jan 2016